Guide to the Authors' Manuscripts
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Authors' Manuscripts,
1923-1982
27.5 linear ft (66 boxes).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4079645
History
Scope and Content
Manuscripts of books and short stories written and published by various authors, many with Columbia University connections. This collection began as the result of a letter sent to authors with Columbia connections asking if they would consider the University Libraries as a place of deposit for the manuscripts of their published works. The collection grows as new authors deposit their works and new manuscripts are added to those already on deposit.
Arrangement
Selected materials cataloged; remainder arranged.
Subjects
Albertson, Dean, 1920-; Anthony, Edward, 1895-; Belo, Jane, 1904-1968.; Borton, Hugh.; Bowden, John Paul, 1904-; Coatsworth, Elizabeth.; Crownfield, Gertrude, 1867-1945.; Dangerfield, George, 1904-1986.; Frankel, Charles, 1917-; Gallagher, Thomas Michael, 1918-; Goldman, Eric Frederick, 1915-1989.; Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1893-1970.; Kaula, Edna Mason.; Lehmann-Haupt, Hellmut, 1903-; Mabee, Carleton, 1914-; Marrin, Albert.; Millner, Simon L.; Molloy, Robert, 1906-1977.; Owens, William.; Paul, Louis.; Quinn, Anthony, 1915-2001.; Reik, Theodor, 1888-1969.; Smith, Helene.; Wald, Abraham, 1902-1950.; Manuscripts.; Short stories.; Authors.
Acquisition
06/--/56 M-56-06
Gift of various authors.
- List of Names
  - Agresti, Oliva R.
  - Albertson, Dean
  - Albertson, Dean, 1920-
  - Anthony, Edward
  - Anthony, Edward, 1895-
  - Ausubel, Herman
  - Belo, Jane, 1904-1968
  - Blaisdell, Dorothea C.
  - Boas, F.?
  - Borton, Hugh
  - Bowden, John Paul, 1904-
  - Brown, Courtney C
  - Buck, John
  - Ch'en Kung-po
  - Coatsworth, Elizabeth
  - Commanger, Henry Steele
  - Crownfield, Gertrude
  - Dangerfield, George
  - Dangerfield, George, 1904-1986
  - Drake-Smith, Daniel
  - Foselle
  - Frankel, Charles, 1917-
  - Gallagher, Thomas Michael, 1918-
  - Geran, John. A. (Conor MacDari)
  - Goldman, Eric Frederick, 1915-
  - Hacker, Louis
  - Hayden, Hiram
  - Hobart, Alice Tisdale
  - Howard, Elizabeth Metzger
  - Jackson, A.V.W.
  - Kaula, Edna Mason
  - Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1893-1970
  - Lehmann-Haupt, Hellmut, 1903-
  - Linderman, Winifred B.
  - Loggins, Vernon
  - Loomis, Roger Sherman
  - Mabee, Carleton, 1914-
  - Marrin, Albert
  - Mason, Henrietta
  - Meyer, Gerard Previn
  - Millner, Simon L.
  - Molloy, Robert, 1906-1977
  - Moore, Austin L.
  - Owens, William
  - Paul, Louis
  - Quinn, Anthony
  - Reik, Theodor, 1888-1969
  - Simmons, Ernest
  - Smith, Helen E.
  - Stafford, Ezra Hurlburt
  - Suther, Marshall
  - Tufts, Anne E.
  - Wald, Abraham, 1902-1950
  - Ward, Grace Faulkner
  - Weingart, Jerry
  - Weingart, Jerry B.
  - Weinstein, Harold
  - Wendriner, Karl George
  - Wycoff, Charles Chandler